Guide to the John W. Cook Interviews with Architects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John W. Cook interviews with architects
1969-1970
MS 1873
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.25
(41 boxes)
The John W. Cook Interviews with Architects consist of recorded interviews conducted with American architects prominent in the mid-to-late 20th century. These interviews were recorded by Cook and Heinrich Klotz in 1969-1970 and largely transcribed in their 1973 book Conversations with Architects, published by Praeger Publishers, New York. The full interview with Louis Kahn was transcribed more recently in Louis I. Kahn in Conversation, edited by Jules David Prown and Karen E. Denavit and published by Yale University Press in 2015.
Cook, John Wesley, 1933-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Wesley Cook, 2003; gift of Karen Denavit and Jules David Prown, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist, must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives website.
Biographical / Historical
John W. Cook is Professor Emeritus of Religion and the Arts at Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The John W. Cook Interviews with Architects consist of recorded interviews conducted with American architects prominent in the mid-to-late 20th century. These interviews were recorded by Cook and Heinrich Klotz in 1969-1970 and largely transcribed in their 1973 book Conversations with Architects, published by Praeger Publishers, New York. The full interview with Louis Kahn was transcribed more recently in Louis I. Kahn in Conversation, edited by Jules David Prown and Karen E. Denavit and published by Yale University Press in 2015.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by architect's last name.
Architects -- United States; Architecture; Goldberg, Bertrand, 1913-1997; Johnson, Philip, 1906-2005; Kahn, Louis I., 1901-1974; Lapidus, Morris; Moore, Charles Willard, 1925-1993; Roche, Kevin, 1922-; Rudolph, Paul, 1918-1997; Scott Brown, Denise, 1931-; Venturi, Robert, 1925-
- Original material, 40
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Goldberg, Bertrand
    - 1969 November 4, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 1–2)
    - Undated, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 3–4)
  - Kahn, Louis I.
    - Tape 1 and Tape 2, 1969 July 15; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 5–6)
      - Use copies, 3 (Box 5Ua–5Ub, Box 6U)
    - Tape 3, 1969 November 6; 1 (Box 7)
      - Use copy, Compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 7U)
    - Tape 4 and Tape 5, 1969 December 7; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 8–9)
      - Use copies, 2 Compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 8Ua–8Ub)
      - Use copies, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 9Ua–9Ub)
        General
        Two use copies of Tape 5, Side B are available. Copy 1 matches the master file, which misses thirteen seconds of dialogue at the end of the recording. Copy 2 includes the thirteen seconds of dialogue missing from the master file, but this dialogue is largely inaudible.
    - Center for British Art Building at Yale, 1969 December 15; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 10–11)
      - Use copies, 3 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 10U, Box 11Ua–11Ub)
    - Tape 6, 1970 April 4; 1 (Box 12)
      - Use copies, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 12Ua–12Ub)
    - Tapes 7-9, 1970 April 5; 3 audiotapes (Reel-to-reel) (Box 13–15)
      - Use copies, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 13Ua–13Ub)
      - Use copies, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 14Ua–14Ub)
      - Use copy, Compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 15U)
  - Lapidus, Morris
    - 1969 April 18, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 22)
    - 1970 April 22, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 23–24)
  - Johnson, Philip
    - 1969 July 26, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 16)
    - 1969 July 29, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 17)
    - 1969 August, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 18–19)
    - 1969 August 14, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 20–21)
  - Moore, Charles
    - 1970 February 25, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 25)
    - 1970 March 4, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 26–27)
    - 1970 April 7, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 28)
  - Roche, Kevin
    - 1969 August 18, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 29)
      - Use copies, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 29Ua–29Ub)
    - 1969 August 18, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 30)
      - Use copy, 2 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 30Ua–30Ub)
    - 1969 October 13-17, 4 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 31–34)
      - Use copies, 8 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 31Ua–31Ub, Box 32Ua–32Ub, Box 33Ua–33Ub, Box 34Ua–34Ub)
  - Rudolph, Paul
    - 1969 November 19, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 35–36)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 35U–36U)
    - 1969 December 14, 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 37–38)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 37U–38U)
    - 1970 April 22, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 39)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 39Ua–39Ub)
  - Venturi, Robert and Denise Scott Brown
    - 1970 May 16, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 40)
- Additional material, 2009-2015; Accession 2015-M-059; 0.25; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  This accession comprises the recorded Louis I. Kahn inteviews with John W. Cook and Heinrich Klotz after the original reel-to-reel audio tape was transferred to compact disc and transcribed in full, as well as indexed.
  - Kahn, Louis I., verbatim interview transcripts and indexes (Box 1)
  - Computer files